[wind rushing]
[man] Good morning.
On this day, July 1st, 2014,
at this hour, 0600.
We are at the very first
airport in the world...
[woman] The topic of so much
controversy over the past seven years
has continued development.
Protests from environmental
groups and a number
of developing countries continue.
But in accordance with...
[man] It had been claimed that CW7
is the answer to global warming.
And we are witnessing it.
[woman] Leaders who argue that global
warming can no longer be ignored.
Today, 79 countries
will began dispersing CW7
into the upper layers
of the atmosphere.
[man] ...in the upper layers
of the atmosphere
and surprisingly bring down
the average global temperature
to the finest levels.
It is just a day away that...
[woman] ...upper layers
of the atmosphere.
According to scientists, the artificial
cooling substance, CW7,
will succeed in bringing average global
temperatures down to manageable levels,
as a revolutionary solution
to mankind's warming of the planet.
- Head check.
- OK.
All right, get in line.
Everybody sit down.
One, two, three,
four, five, six.
Keep going.
Go on.
Hey you, sit down.
Curtis, sit down.
Sit down.
I said sit down!
- What the fuck are you doing?
- Counting.
Can't you sit and count?
Do you want to get shot? You're crazy.
Shut up, Edgar. I'm thinking.
Are there any experienced
violinists here?
Raise your hands.
- Violinist!
- Stand up, come forward.
[soldier] Food, come and get it.
Violinists? Are they're having a laugh?
Those bastards in the front
sections think they own us.
Eating their steak dinners and listening
to string quartets and that.
We'll be different when we get there.
[sighs] I want steak.
Excuse me, sir.
My wife and I played violin
in the Boston Symphony Orchestra.
I was first chair.
Can you still play?
Of course, you never forget.
Show me your hands.
Leave your belongings,
we just need your hands.
- Not both?
- Yes, both hands.
My wife, Doris, plays beautifully.
Better than me, even.
They just need one person.
Then I won't go.
[woman] Doris. Doris!
- [woman screams]
- No! [shouting]
- [bones snapping]
- [Doris screams]
[soldier] Sit down, everyone!
- Sit down.
- No, they can't just...
Sit down.
Those fucking bastards.
Now isn't the time.
Well, when is the time?
Soon.
Doris. I'll be back, Doris.
It's all right.
I'll come back.
What does steak taste like again?
I had it once, but I can't remember.
[Curtis] If you can't remember
then it's better to forget.
All right, then. What does it
smell like when it's cooking and that?
When it's emanating
around the place.
Curtis, is this it?
- It's not it.
- No.
- Hey, I heard that...
- [woman] Curtis, here!
Timbo.
How's it hanging, buddy?
Give me a pound.
Blow it up.
[makes explosion sound]
Hey, listen.
I think I need that protein block.
How about I trade you,
this one for that one?
Mmm...
No?
Nice bargaining powers, Curtis.
Here, give me this one,
- I'll give you that...
- Relax, relax.
Come here, Timmy.
Come here.
Come right... ooh... [grunts]
I have an idea.
I will give you this one
and that one for that one.
- What do you say?
- No.
- Go get him.
- [sighing]
Timmy!
Timothy, your mom is gonna give
you a damn good spanking.
I don't know where the fuck he went.
Hey, come here.
Give us it. Give us it.
All right, Jose,
how are you doing, man?
- [man] Get off!
- Timmy, off you go.
[indistinct chattering]
Edgar, why did you
let him get up there?
I didn't, He got up there by himself.
He's very nimble.
- He's five.
- He's a very nimble five year old.
[mother] Timmy, sweetie, come down.
Hey, come here.
What do you want for it?
In the whole wide train?
In the whole wide train.
The ball.
The ball? No.
No, I'm sorry I can't do that.
I can't do that.
Yes, I get the ball
for a whole hour.
[exhales]
Done.
Curtis. Is it time?
Not yet, Tanya. Soon.
[horn blasting]
[Edgar] Red letter?
Yeah, it's the one
we've been waiting for.
Our informant gave us a name.
N-A-M...
[Curtis] Nam Kung Min Soo.
He's a security expert.
He's in the prison section now.
Wait, you're joking right?
- He's in prison?
- Hey, out of here.
No, I'm just saying,
what kind of chance do we have?
- Edgar.
- I just think if this guy
says that he's such
a great security expert,
- why can't he just break himself...
- That's enough. Go.
Let's go, Tim.
Come on, let's go.
Edgar just wants to help, you know.
Thinks the world of you.
He shouldn't worship me
the way he does.
I'm not who he thinks I am.
Few of us ever are.
All right, we're here.
Tail section, quarantine
section, prison section.
Gate, gate, gate.
Four seconds when all three
gates are open at once.
We have four seconds to go through
three gates and bust Nam out.
Then Nam gets us the rest of the way.
Our fate depends on this man.
Yeah.
If we can get him to cooperate,
he can take us
all the way to the front of the train.
Very front section?
Yeah.
From here right
to the front of the train.
Everything in one stroke.
We control the engine,
we control the world.
Without that, we have nothing.
All past revolutions have failed
because they couldn't take the engine.
What are you saying?
This time we take the engine.
Then what?
- We kill them.
- Wilford?
You should run the train now,
not Wilford.
I am a shadow
of my former shadow.
My day was decades ago.
[Edgar] How old is Gilliam?
Shut up, Edgar.
I'm not saying
that I want that to happen.
That's not what I'm saying.
What I mean is he will die someday.
And when that happens,
you're gonna have to take over.
You're gonna have to run the train.
I'm not a leader.
I don't know.
I think you'd be pretty good
if you ask me.
-Hey, Edgar
-Hmm?
How far back can you remember?
I don't know, like what?
Your mother, you remember her?
I can remember her face...
...every once in a while.
But it's not clear.
- [door clatters]
- [man] Stay down, everybody.
- Everybody stay in your place.
- [man 2] Fucking look at me.
[man] Keep down, keep down.
Easy.
- Medical inspection.
- All the kids come with me.
Just the kids.
- Just a medical check up.
- [man 3] Medical inspection.
- You're doing good.
- Everybody, all the kids.
- [woman] All the kids? Again?
- That's right, just come.
Stay back there, ma'am.
Just stay back there.
Hello, what's this?
One more. Yup, come on.
- You need to go.
- We don't need to do that.
- There's nothing wrong with him.
- It's just a medical check.
You just stay back there.
Come on, that's right.
Come join the others, OK.
[man] You, go and check.
- [man 2] Don't move.
- Go, Timmy! Go!
- Run!
- No!
[all shouting]
Timmy!
[commotion continues]
- That's her baby!
- Please!
Andy! Andy!
Give me back my son!
Give me my son, you fucking bitch!
Andy! Andy!
[man] Why did you let him
throw his shoe?!
[shouting continues]
- [Curtis] Timmy! Timmy!
- Timmy!
At this altitude,
we need only seven minutes.
[clock ticking]
[wind howling]
[screaming]
[hissing, thud]
[screaming stops]
Seven minutes allotted
for your speech, sir.
[translating in different
foreign languages]
No, no, we don't need all that,
I've only got seven minutes.
[metal clattering]
Passengers.
This is not a shoe.
This is disorder.
This is size-ten chaos.
This, see this? This is death.
In this locomotive we call home,
there is one thing that,
between our warm hearts
and the bitter cold...
- [sobbing]
- Clothing? Jeans? No, order.
Order is the barrier that holds
back the frozen death.
We must all of us,
on this train of life,
remain in our allotted station.
We must each of us,
occupy our preordained
particular position.
Would you wear a shoe
on your head?
Of course you wouldn't wear
a shoe on your head.
A shoe doesn't belong in your head.
A shoe belongs on your foot.
A hat belongs on your head.
I am a hat, you are a shoe.
I belong on the head,
you belong on the foot.
Yes? So it is.
In the beginning, order was
prescribed by your ticket.
First class, economy,
and freeloaders like you.
Eternal order is prescribed
by the Sacred Engine.
All things flow
from the Sacred Engine.
All things in their place.
All passengers in their section.
All water flowing, all heat rising,
pays homage to the Sacred Engine.
In its own particular
preordained position.
So it is.
Now, as in the beginning,
I belong to the front.
You belong to the tail.
When the foot seeks
the place of the head
a sacred line is crossed.
Know your place.
Keep your place.
Be a shoe.
Well, we have 42 seconds left.
So we can go to comment
of Mr. Wilford,
the divine keeper
of the Sacred Engine.
[beeping]
Sir? Mr. Wilford?
- [radio static]
- Are you there?
Are you there, sir?
[static continues]
Oh, it's breaking up.
Oh, well.
Mr. Wilford's a very busy man.
So it is.
[timer dings]
- Are we just gonna watch?
- Not now.
I'm not just gonna fucking sit here.
[spoon clanking]
[arm shatters]
[screaming]
No, I'm all right.
Stop. Stop right there. Sit down.
Put that useless gun down.
Put it away.
Long time no see, Mr. Gilliam.
It's a pleasure!
You look healthy.
He's fine.
Minister Mason, please deliver
a message to Mr. Wilford.
Certainly, what shall I say?
Tell him he and I need to talk.
Well, you can talk to me.
Mr. Wilford has no reason
to visit here.
Not here.
At the front.
[Edgar speaking indistinctly]
Your son will be a hero, I promise.
Or daughter, whatever it is.
I got it. I got it.
Your contribution has
been duly noted. Thanks.
[shouting]
So sorry to interrupt you
while you're praying.
What are you doing, man?
So sorry.
[both speaking foreign language]
There's your Buddha back,
thanks very much.
[man continues
in foreign language]
Move, move, move, move,
move, move, move!
- [man] Stop fooling around.
- Whoo! Oh!
I've got a better batch.
Stronger, fresh, uncut.
Want to try some?
How many protein blocks for
ten rocks of uncut kronole?
[indistinct chattering]
They don't have bullets.
[Gilliam] Why do you say that?
[Curtis] You remember
what Mason said?
She said, "Put down that useless gun."
She meant she wouldn't give
the order to shoot me.
No.
No, I think the guns
are literally useless.
They used up all their bullets
four years ago, in the last revolt.
Bullets are extinct.
If you're wrong, we could be
finished before we even start.
I think we should be patient.
Wait for the next red letter.
[group chants] One, two.
One, two.
[Curtis] To the left and right.
Not yet! Up, up. Now left.
[group continues]
One, two. One, two.
[man shouting orders, indistinct]
Hello? Andrew.
Andrew!
Wake up. Rise and shine.
When you dream too much of the sun,
you forget the trees.
I believe this is your son.
I'm s... I'm sorry, it's not very good.
It's not my best work.
It's a little dark.
But, if you look
very deep into the eyes,
you can see a little bit of hope.
What about my boy?
You got one of Timmy?
Oh, yes, Tanya. I do.
Easy, easy.
Come off this easy.
Don't hurt yourself.
Here. There you go. Timmy.
[wistful chuckle] Look at him.
That little... That little smile.
Curtis, you gotta
let me come with you.
No, Tanya, I'm sorry.
You will be if you
don't let me come.
I'm going to the front and
I'm gonna make that bitch sorry
- she put her hands on my boy.
- Make this one tighter.
You know I'm stronger than all these
skinny-ass soldiers anyway.
Please.
- [alarm blares]
- [Edgar] Shit, what's going on?
Change of schedule, boys.
Move it back. Now or never.
Don't panic.
Stick with the plan.
Hide that, hide your weapons
in your clothes.
- Head check.
- Yeah, yeah.
Line up.
All right, sit down.
One. Two. Three.
What the fuck do we do?
[soldier] Five. Six. Keep going.
I've had enough of this
protein block bullshit.
Yeah, this is bullshit!
- We're fucking hungry!
- [Tanya] I want chicken.
We're not gonna sit down
for this shit.
We want chicken!
Chicken!
[all shouting]
[soldier] Quiet! Be quiet!
Calm down. It's OK.
You want him fucking dead?
Is that it?
Keep quiet.
Still going for it, are we?
Come on, let's go!
Let's do it.
The rifles.
No, we can overwhelm them.
We easily outnumber their bullets.
[Gilliam] This is it.
Curtis, come on.
We're out of time,
we gotta do it now.
They've got no bullets!
[chaotic shouting]
Move! Keep going!
Keep going, keep going!
Close the gate quick! Shut it!
- [grunting]
- [crowd shouting]
[grunting]
[fighters grunt and shout]
I'm fine, Grey. You go now.
[crowd cheering]
[guard screams]
Fuck.
Nam Koong Min Soo.
Kronole addict.
That explains a lot, doesn't it?
- Hurry up, Edgar.
- Hurry up?
So sorry for keeping
you all waiting.
Obviously, I work here so...
[clicks]
- Open it.
- Here we go.
[Edgar] Hey.
Kronole head.
So this is kronole?
I hear it's pretty big
in the front section.
Careful, that's how
these guys hallucinate.
It's industrial waste.
And it's highly flammable.
Are you Nam Koong Min Soo,
security specialist?
Did you design all the door locks
and security systems on the train?
[Edgar] Look at him man, he's gone.
Look at his eyes.
He's fried his brain
with that fucking shite.
Are you Nam?
[sighs]
Nam, are you listening?
[device translates into Korean]
[speaks Korean]
[device translates]
Yes, I'm listening, fuck.
[speaking Korean]
Unknown words found. Please
try again with correct vocabulary.
We need your help.
For what?
We're going to the front.
And we need you
to open up the gates.
What if I say no?
Uncut, straight from the barrel.
Every door you open,
you get one lump of kronole.
Jesus, Marlboro Light?
[man] I can't believe it.
Cigarettes have been extinct
for more than ten years now.
Want one?
I won't waste it on a prick like you.
I'm gonna make this
real simple for you.
You help us, you get your drug.
If not, we put you back
where we found you.
What'll it be, asshole?
[Edgar] Chan.
Chan, get out of here.
Let's get out. Hey.
[crowd clamoring]
Come here!
Hey, that's enough.
Put him back
in the fucking drawer!
Get up.
[device] My daughter, Yona.
- If I go, she goes, too.
- So you're coming with us?
[speaking Korean]
[device] One gate,
two lumps of kronole.
She's an addict, too?
[belches]
[electricity zapping]
[doors rumbling]
[sighs]
[continues zapping]
[rumbling continues]
Nobody there.
Kronole?
[inhales deeply]
[exhales]
[inhales]
[indistinct chattering]
[Tanya] Look at all these beds.
Where is everybody?
[Edgar] Looks like
they left in a hurry.
[man] There's food on the table.
This can't be a window, can it?
Still cold.
Dead.
All dead.
All right, let's go everyone.
Stay focused.
We didn't come here for this.
You heard the man, let's go.
Come on, move. Move.
Nam! Nam!
Kronole.
How did you know
there was nobody there?
He's running.
Paul?
Paul! What the hell is he doing?
- Paul!
- [Curtis] He looks so different.
Just a second.
It's used to be automatic,
but parts went extinct.
- [grunts]
- It's not the Paul I remember.
No. Paul? It's Curtis!
They ain't coming back,
so now I gotta do it...
[grunting]
Whoo! ...manually.
[machine whirring]
Mmm, still hot.
Look at them all.
You do some nice work.
That's right man,
there's your food.
There's your protein blocks.
Is this why they took you?
To make this garbage?
- [Paul] Huh?
- Paul?
You've been alone
this whole time?
Huh. Alone. Ha-ha!
In the zone.
We're going to the front.
Come with us.
All right, you're going
to the front? Yeah, man!
But no way, man.
My place is here, all right?
Here? Making this crap? Why?
[gasps loudly]
[gasps sharply]
[panting]
[Curtis] You can't draw this.
OK.
[loud rock music plays]
Oh, man.
All this time,
we've been eating this shit?
Hey. I eat them too, you know?
Every single day.
Where'd you get this?
[stammers]
Have you been the one writing these?
Man, I don't write them.
[stammers]
Why do you have this?
Who gave this to you?
They just leave them for me, man.
I put them in the protein blocks.
I send them on. That's it.
The water supply section?
Yeah, it's just a few cars up.
It's where the water's
cleansed and recycled.
It's one of the most crucial
sections in the train.
[Curtis] If we take it,
we have the upper hand?
We don't even have to go
to the very front.
We control the water...
...we control the negotiation.
Uh, hi. Hi. Excuse me,
sorry to bother you there.
Could I get you a glass
of water to speed this up?
Listen, would you get on with it, man?
You're keeping us all fucking waiting!
- [device] Am I?
- [Edgar] Yeah, you are.
Although you have been fucking
smelling that flammable shite,
that time is a probably a distant
fucking concept for you, isn't it?
Of course,
I'm only doing this for kronole.
Here we go again.
Kronole this, kronole that.
Christ almighty man,
do some fucking work.
You're the ones
who keep giving it to me.
Are you a bit thick?
That's what you asked for
each time you opened the gate.
[Nam] So that's what I'm doing.
[voices continue, indistinct]
Yona? It's Yona right?
How old are you?
Seventeen.
Seventeen? You're a train baby then.
How about you?
Seventeen years on earth.
Seventeen years in the tail section.
Earth?
What was it like?
I don't remember.
Why?
I don't want to remember
anything before I met Gilliam.
Yona...
...are you clairvoyant?
Clairvoyant? What's that?
Well, you always seem to know
what's behind the gates.
Do you see things in your mind?
Don't open it.
[Curtis] What?
Lock the gate!
[zaps]
Be careful.
Yeah.
You, too.
[chaotic shouting]
Team two, move!
Move forward!
[blade ringing]
[sounds fade]
[slow-motion, muffled shouting]
[slow-motion splattering sounds]
[fighting sounds resume]
[horn blares]
Passing Yekaterina bridge!
[woman on PA in foreign language]
We're at the bridge, guys!
[all counting] Ten, nine, eight,
seven, six, five, four,
three, two, one!
Happy New Year!
I hate getting old,
I fucking hate it.
[shouting in foreign language]
- Everybody down!
- Hang on!
Impact!
Not yet! A second one!
Stay down!
Hey, Nam, what are you doing?!
What are you doing?!
He's high as a fucking kite.
Here it comes.
Safe passage.
[translates]
[fighting grunts resume]
- [man] Hey, watch it!
- [shouting stops]
[man] What was that?
[clears throat grotesquely]
One, two. One, two.
Happy Yekaterina bridge,
you filthy ingrates.
You people, who, were it not
for the benevolent Wilford,
would have frozen solid
18 years ago today...
You people, who have suckled
the generous titty of Wilford
ever since, for food and shelter.
And now, in front of
our hallowed water
supply section no less,
you repay his kindness
with violent hooliganism.
You scum.
Precisely 74 percent of you shall die.
My friend, you suffer from
the misplaced optimism of the doomed.
This is going to be good.
Curtis...
[Nam speaks Korean]
What? What did he say?
He said you guys are fucked.
[Nam speaking Korean]
[Yona] You stupid tail sectioners.
There's a tunnel right after
Yekaterina Bridge.
- A tunnel?
- Mm-hm.
A fucking long one.
[Nam speaking Korean]
Everybody back!
- Go, go, go!
- [all shouting]
[silence]
[soft grunting]
- [groans]
- [screams]
[chaotic shouting]
[Curtis] Chan, get out, get out.
Chan! We need fire!
[Edgar] Chan, bring the fire!
[indistinct shouting]
[cheering]
[snarling]
[war cry]
Crush you, motherfucker!
Officer Fuyu!
What are you doing?
Don't look at me, you dozy boger!
Look there!
[crowd roaring]
Put me down,
stop squeezing my leg.
Surrender!
Surrender, he'll kill me
if we don't surrender.
Shit.
[screams]
[slow motion grunting]
[Edgar] Curtis!
[no audio]
Stop!
Stop everybody!
Drop your weapons!
Stop!
[Curtis] Everybody stop!
Do what he says,
for crying out loud.
[Curtis] Drop your weapons!
[blade stabbing]
[gasping]
[grunts]
Don't look.
Survivors.
Wash yourselves.
The water supply section.
Wash away the blood.
[Tanya] Have you
seen these kids? Hmm?
I... I don't know anything about...
- [screams]
- [ax clangs on metal]
Where are they, you bitch?
I don't know, I don't know.
It's not me.
It's not me. [whimpering]
Tell us or we'll cut your
fucking arm off
even shorter than mine,
you bastard.
Wilford! Wilford knows.
Wilford...
Wilford likes kids.
He does.
That's why he sends that yellow one,
Claude, to get them for him.
It's Wilford you want, not me!
[Gilliam] Wilford likes kids?
All he cares about
is his wretched engine.
The engine is sacred.
And Wilford is divine.
Wilford is merciful.
Call him.
See if he'll come save you.
[Gilliam] Yes.
Wilford the merciful.
Call him.
He won't come here,
he won't leave his engine.
We're gonna rip you
into little pieces.
He still won't come?
Well, we control the water.
We turn that off,
he'll have to come.
Turn off the water?
You'll only be condemning
your own people.
The water comes from the front.
The nose of the train,
it breaks up the snow and ice
and turns it into water,
like an elephant's trunk.
The water comes in the mouth.
Not in the bum, Curtis.
Yes, Wilford knows you well,
Mr. Curtis Everett.
He's been watching you.
And we know you won't harm
your own people.
Too bad you couldn't save
your second in command.
What was his name? Edgar?
- Shut the fuck up!
- Curtis! Curtis, I can help you!
You can fucking die,
is what you can do.
No, I can help you. I swear it.
Listen... Listen to me.
Wilford won't come here.
He's not coming.
You've got to go to him.
And I can take you.
I know the train,
I can guarantee you safe passage.
Why the fuck would I trust you?
Because I want to live.
So you'd sell out
Wilford the Benevolent?
If I take you to the front,
you have to kill him.
I'll get you close enough.
You kill him and let me live.
Curtis?
Are you still determined
to push ahead?
Of course.
We're not even half way.
You already got further
than anyone else.
Better than MacGregor,
four years ago.
Ten cars, 20 cars, it doesn't matter
unless you make it to the engine.
They'll just regroup
and attack us again.
We gotta pull them out by the roots.
So many have been killed.
We've lost so many.
I know.
Seen our men?
They're exhausted.
I told them to wash themselves...
...so that I can assess the damage.
Let me go ahead.
I got Mason now,
I can move a lot faster.
You stay here with the wounded
and guard the prisoners.
Let me take the engine,
I'll call for you to lead us.
Stop it, Curtis.
Why are you doing that?
You know very well that you're
already our leader.
You have to accept that now.
How can I lead if I have two good arms.
It's faded a lot.
Better to have both arms.
You can't do a lot with one,
you know?
Especially when you hold a woman.
Much better to have two arms,
wouldn't you agree?
When you get to the narrow bridge,
big gate with a "W" on it...
...Wilford's behind that.
Don't let Wilford talk.
Cut out his tongue.
[man] OK, let's all get in there.
Squeeze in.
- [laughing]
- [man] Perfect, perfect.
The hat becomes you well.
Now, Grey...
...you must go with Curtis.
[man] Oops, forgot somebody.
OK.
Kronole.
[water spraying lightly]
[harpsichord plays gentle music]
Don't mind me, back to work, everyone.
Back to work.
- Minister, are you OK?
- Yes, I'm fine.
- Please don't eat it. Don't eat it.
- No, no. They're very friendly.
They won't bite.
Well, they might bite a tomato, but...
Can I eat this?
Train baby like you wouldn't know.
I grew up walking on this every day.
This is what's under all the snow.
Earth!
What's this?
It's moving. Lives under the...
What's that?
Hey.
Do any of you feel like sushi?
Hell, yeah.
Line that shit up.
Right? [chuckles]
[Mason] You people are very lucky.
This is only served twice in a year.
In January and July.
Why? Not enough fish?
Oh, enough is not the criterion.
Balance. You see,
this aquarium is a closed
ecological system.
And the number of individual units
must be very closely,
precisely controlled
in order to maintain the proper
sustainable balance.
No, you eat this.
You know what that's made of?
Dig in.
Curtis, my friend,
do you think that we might
dispense with the restraints
for this next section?
I'm not your friend.
And why would I?
Uh, for the...
for the sake of the young?
Education?
[excited squealing and shouting]
- Quiet!
- Good morning, children.
I'm pleased to present guests
from tail section.
[woman] Yes, what do we say
to tail section guests, children?
[kids] Good morning,
tail section guests!
Timmy!
[Andrew] Andy?
- Timmy...?
- Andy? Andy?
This little boy,
his name is Timmy.
This is my son.
Please, take a good look at the picture.
- I saw them.
- When?
- Where?
- Came through there,
went through there.
Is that all, boy?
Yes.
Were they crying?
No, but they looked like they wanted to.
I heard old tail sectioners
were lazy dogs who slept
all day in their own shit.
No, they're very nice!
And very just and merciful.
So it is.
Minister Mason, we were
just about to show a video.
- Very good.
- [TV turns on]
[intro music plays]
[children] Wilford!
[man narrates] From a very young age,
Mr. Wilford's love
of locomotives was apparent.
When I grow up,
I'll live on a train forever.
[children] Forever!
His early dreams were realized
when he founded
his transportation empire,
the Wilford Industries.
But his greatest dream was to construct
a luxury locomotive cruise line,
connecting railways
of the entire world into one.
[man] A circular railway that extends
for 438,000 kilometers,
and completes
one circle every year.
Impervious to the extreme cold
of the Arctic,
and the scorching
heat of the African desert,
Wilford's miracle train
is self-sustaining,
possesses the most
sophisticated design,
- and advanced technology known...
- [TV turns off]
As hard as it is to believe,
people in the old world
made fun of Mr. Wilford.
They criticized him
for over-engineering
and over-equipping this wonderful train.
But Mr. Wilford knew
something they did not.
And what was that?
Old world people are frigging morons
who got turned into popsicles.
[teacher] Well, sort of.
Mr. Wilford knew that CW7
would freeze the world.
So what did the prophetic
Mr. Wilford invent
to protect the chosen
from that calamity?
The Engine!
Rumble, rumble, rattle, rattle
It will never die!
What happens if the engine stops?
We all freeze and die
But will it stop? Oh, will it stop?
-  No! No!
-  Can you tell us why?
The engine is eternal, yes!
The engine is forever, yes!
Rumble, rumble, rattle, rattle
Who is the reason why?
Wilford, yeah
[all] Wilford! Wilford!
Hip hurray!
Oh, I love that one.
Such a tonic.
- Oh, it's time children, come this way.
- [children squealing]
Don't trip now.
Don't push, there's plenty of room.
Now, Who can tell me what's coming up?
[children] The Frozen Seven!
Pay attention, this tableau
will surely be on the exam.
Fifteen years ago,
in the third year of the train,
seven passengers tried to stop
Wilford's miracle train
and go outside.
And what do we call this event,
Magdalena?
The Revolt of the Seven.
Very good.
Long before you were born.
Of course they failed
to stop the train.
Instead they jumped out
of the running train.
Here they come now.
[Nam] You look, too.
Why?
There they are.
That's how far they made it.
That's a woman in the front.
A cleaning lady from the front section.
She was an Inuit.
You know, Eskimo.
She taught me
about every type of snow and ice.
She believed we could
survive outside the train.
If we ever go outside the train?
[all] We'd all freeze and die.
[teacher] If the engine stops running?
[all] We'd all die.
And who takes care
of the Sacred Engine?
[children] Mr. Wilford.
[melodic chimes play]
Children, it's the New Year eggs
from Mr. Wilford.
Touch them, they are still warm.
These eggs are boiled using water
heated by the Sacred Engine itself.
As a special treat,
we have playing for us
the world renowned first chair violinist
of the Boston Symphony Orchestra,
Mr. Gerald McInster.
[children cheering]
Is that really Gerald?
He looks damn great.
- [violin plays]
- Happy New Year.
No, thank you very much.
Let's go, Curtis.
Happy new year.
Oh! I thought the chicken
was extinct.
There are actually many things on
board that were rumored to be extinct.
Such as?
This.
[all screaming]
Andrew! No!
[gasps]
[gunshot]
It wasn't me.
[horn blows on TV]
[Curtis] No.
- [gun fires]
- [Tanya screams]
[Tanya, faint] Curtis.
[louder, more clear] Curtis!
You have to lead us.
Curtis, my friend,
we understand each other.
Listen to my words, it wasn't me!
[empty clip clatters on the floor]
[loads new clip]
[exhales] We go forward.
[Nam] Now!
Open!
[door hissing open]
- It's Mason.
- Shit, check her pulse.
- [gunfire]
- [people screaming]
Hey, hey! Fire regulation
to minimize dam...
[empty chamber clicks]
[empty chamber clicking]
God, that did not look good.
He's coming.
[indistinct chattering]
[screams]
Hurry, hurry. He's got
a master key, right?
Wait, don't shoot.
Please don't shoot.
You just killed a front
section passenger! I'm report...
I didn't see a thing.
Where are you going?
Just wait a minute!
Could we talk about it
just for one second?
[groans]
You son of a bitch!
[screams]
[bones breaking]
[whimpers]
Close the door, jerk.
[all shouting]
[Nam groaning]
[both grunting]
[screams]
[panting]
Tanya.
My Timmy.
[muttering]
[sobs]
We're gonna find him.
I promise.
I know.
Thank you.
[electronic dance music playing]
[sniffs] You grab some, too.
[woman shrieking]
[man] Hey, I want my kronole!
Hey, turn around, motherfucker.
You got my kronole.
- I want that shit.
- [woman] Hey, asshole, give it back!
[angry shouting]
[man] What the fuck
you think you're doing?
[muffled shouting]
[machines churning loudly]
[intoxicated Yona laughing]
[Yona singing, unintelligible]
[continues laughing]
[Yona moaning]
Open the door.
Huh?
Kronole first. Kronole.
Kronole? You want kronole?
- Here. Take it.
- [grunting]
Open it!
Open the gate!
You're crazy!
[both men grunting]
[moaning]
What the hell's wrong with you?
You and your fucking gates.
Here, have a smoke.
[device beeps]
[speaking Korean]
[device] You should be grateful.
That's the world's last cigarette,
you tail section pig.
You ever been to the tail section?
[device translating]
Do you have any idea
what went on back there?
When we boarded?
It was chaos.
Yeah, we didn't freeze to death,
but we didn't have time to be thankful.
Wilford's soldiers came
and they took everything.
It was a thousand people
in an iron box.
No food, no water.
After a month, we ate the weak.
[crying softly]
You know what I hate about myself?
I know what people taste like.
I know that babies taste best.
There was a woman.
She was hiding with her baby.
Then some men with knives came.
They killed her
and they took her baby.
And then an old man...
No relation, just an old man,
stepped forward and he said:
"Give me the knife."
Everyone thought he'd
kill the baby himself.
But he took the knife...
...and he cut off his arm.
And he said,
"Eat this if you're so hungry.
Eat this, just leave the baby."
I had never seen anything like that.
And the men put down their knives.
Probably guessed who that old man was.
That baby was Edgar.
And I was the man with the knife.
I killed Edgar's mother.
And then one by one,
other people in the tail section
started cutting off arms and legs
and offering them.
It was like a miracle.
And I wanted to.
I tried.
A month later, Wilford's soldiers
brought those protein blocks.
We've been eating that shit ever since.
Eighteen years I've hated Wilford.
Eighteen years I've waited
for this moment.
And now I'm here.
Open the gate.
Please.
Thanks for your story, Curtis.
But I don't want to open the gate.
I want to open the gate...
...but not this gate.
That one.
The gate to the outside world.
It's been frozen shut for 18 years.
You might take it as a wall.
But it's a fucking gate.
Let's open it and just get the hell out.
And freeze to death?
What are you, fucking crazy?
What if we don't?
What if we could survive outside?
Remember the Yekaterina Bridge?
When your guys were getting chopped up?
There's something
I look at every New Year.
A crashed airplane under the snow.
All I saw ten years ago
was just the tail.
Now the body and wings are peeking out.
Less ice and snow means...
...it's melting.
The type of snow that's about to melt.
A little push and it all falls down.
And you know what I saw recently?
Outside the window, there was...
[laughing]
Never mind...
No need to tell you this.
You gotta take it easy
on that kronole.
Snorting that flammable shit's
gonna fry your brain.
That's exactly right.
Think of what kronole is.
This fucking flammable
industrial waste...
Light it up, and boom.
It's a bomb you idiot.
I didn't stock this shit
for years just to get high.
It's to blow up this gate.
Give me the matches.
What the fuck are you doing?
- Give it to me.
- Take that off the door.
[grunts] Fire!
[gun fires]
Curtis Everett.
I've been asked to extend
a formal invitation
from Mr. Wilford
to join him for dinner.
After you.
Curtis? Is that you?
Curtis, dear boy.
Come in.
Let's take a look at you.
You hungry?
You did a man's work,
coming all this way.
Please, sit down.
You are the first human being
to have walked the total length
of this train, tail to engine.
Did you know that?
Well done. Bravo.
None of your people have ever
been here, to the engine.
I've never been to the tail section.
Why not? Too dirty for you?
Don't want to rub against
the vermin of the tail section?
Do you think my station is
without its own drawbacks?
It's noisy.
And it's lonely.
Right.
Steaks. Plenty of room.
This whore to bring you
anything you want.
Curtis, everyone has their
preordained position.
And everyone is in their place
except you.
That's what people in the best place say
to the people in the worst place.
There's not a soul on this train
who wouldn't trade places with you.
- Would you trade places with me?
- Fuck you.
Curtis, dear boy,
the fact is, we are all stuck
inside this blasted train.
We are all prisoners
in this hunk of metal.
Medium rare?
And this train is
a closed ecosystem.
We must always strive for balance.
Air, water, food supply...
Population must always
be kept in balance.
For optimum balance, however,
there have been times when more
radical solutions were required,
when the population needed
to be reduced, rather...
...drastically.
[all screaming]
We don't have time
for true natural selection.
We would all be hideously over-crowded
and starved, waiting for that.
The next best solution
is to have individual units
kill off other individual units.
From time to time, we've
had to stir the pot, so to speak.
The Revolt of the Seven,
the MacGregor Riots,
the Great Curtis Revolution.
A blockbuster production
with a devilishly unpredictable plot.
Who could have predicted
your counter attack
with the torch
in the Yekaterina Tunnel?
Pure genius.
That wasn't what Gilliam
and I had in our plan.
What?
Don't tell me you didn't know.
Gilliam and I... our plan.
Gilliam?
Gilliam.
The front and the tail are
supposed to work together.
He was more than a partner, really.
- He was my friend.
- Bullshit.
I don't believe you.
Our original agreement
was for the insurgency
to end at the Yekaterina Tunnel.
And all the survivors would go
back to the tail section
- to enjoy much more space.
- You're a fucking liar.
Gilliam would never do that.
It all worked out in the end.
Your counter attack actually made
the insurgency ten times more exciting.
Unfortunately, the front suffered
more losses than anticipated
and Gilliam had to...
[clicks tongue] ...pay the price.
Ironic, isn't it?
How people dramatically cross that
thin barrier between life and death.
Now there's just
one last thing for us to do.
Tally up the numbers.
[telephone ringing]
Hello Wilford, it's me.
I'm at Gilliam's place.
Hold on.
Is it still the same number?
Yes, it still stands at 74 percent.
OK, carry on.
Oh, wait.
Spare 18, to celebrate our 18th year.
It's an excellent idea.
Yes.
- [gunfire]
- [people screaming]
Your people.
Goddamn it, Claude!
Mind the Engine!
She's getting sensitive recently.
Sit down and
mind your table manners.
Just relax.
Calm down.
Boy, now I can see what Gilliam meant.
He told me you were brilliant
and clever, but always so tense.
When's the last time
you got laid? Hmm?
Like Gilliam said, holding a woman
is much better with two arms.
[panting]
I'll miss Gilliam. [soft chuckle]
I'll miss our
late night phone chats.
Oh, he could go on for hours.
All with only one arm.
What's with that face?
Hmm? What's the matter?
You look like a crazy person.
As if there aren't enough
crazies on this train.
[clattering]
[gasps] Blood!
Are you OK?
[groaning]
What happened?
Get down!
[Yona screaming]
[both grunting]
- [screams]
- [bones snapping]
- [weapons clanking]
- [angry chatter]
[coughing] Yona!
We need to open that
gate and get the kronole!
See the wires inside?
A shit load!
Kill you, punk!
I believe it is easier for
someone to survive on this train
if they have some level of insanity.
I mean, as Gilliam well understood,
we need to maintain a proper
balance of anxiety and fear,
chaos and horror,
in order to keep life going.
And if we don't have that,
we need to invent it.
In that sense, the Great Curtis
Revolution you invented
was truly a masterpiece.
Yona! Red goes into eight!
No, seven, seven!
Come with me, Curtis.
Something I want to show you.
You deserve it.
Come on.
She's waking up now.
[engine humming]
[Wilford] Cozy, yes?
Peaceful.
You are now in her heart.
I've devoted my entire life to this.
The Eternal Engine.
It is eternity itself.
Have you ever been
alone on this train?
When was the last time
you were alone?
You can't remember, can you?
So please do take your time.
[panting]
[sobbing]
I just wrote it.
It's for you, Curtis.
Here.
I am old.
I want you to take my station.
It's what you always wanted.
It's what Gilliam wanted, too.
You must tend the engine,
keep her humming.
Look, Curtis...
...beyond the gate.
Section after section,
precisely where they've always been
and where they'll always be,
all adding up to what?
The train.
And now, the perfectly correct
number of human beings,
all in their proper places,
all adding up to what?
Humanity.
The train is the world.
We, the humanity.
And now you have the sacred
responsibility to lead all of humanity.
Without you, Curtis,
humanity will cease to exist.
You've seen what people do
without leadership.
They devour one another.
[angry shouting]
[gate rumbling]
[screams]
[glass shatters]
Yona, the kronole!
- Yona, stop!
- No.
[gun clicking]
No bullets?
Put the kronole on the gate!
Look at them.
That's how people are.
You know.
You've seen this.
You've been this.
Ridiculous.
Pathetic, aren't they?
You can save them from themselves.
This is what Gilliam saved you for.
Curtis...
...this is your destiny.
- It's ready!
- Curtis has the matches!
Curtis! The match!
The space only allows
for a very small person.
Young children under 5.
The engine lasts forever,
but not so all of its parts.
That piece of equipment
went extinct recently.
We needed a replacement.
Thank goodness the tail section
manufactures
a steady supply of kids.
So we can keep going manually.
[grunting]
You fucking bastard!
[Curtis shouts in pain]
[motor powers down]
Yona...
Take the fire.
[both shouting]
It's the last one!
[motor begins to hum]
[motor struggles to resume]
Come on.
[automated voice]
Please stand at a safe distance.
[voice continues, indistinct]
Please stand at safe distance.
Andy? Is that you?
[grunts] Andy!
Do you remember me?
Andy, stop, listen to me.
Don't go up those stairs. Listen!
Andy!
Come here, come over here.
Andy, listen to me!
Get out of there!
[engine humming]
[Curtis groans]
Goddamn it Andy, listen to me!
Oh, Curtis, don't be so melodramatic.
You know everyone has their own
preordained position.
[dramatic music builds]
- [bones snapping]
- [screams]
[electric zapping]
[grunting]
[panting]
- Nice.
- [panting] Huh?
[faint rumbling]
[snow cracking]
[faint rumbling continues]
[all screaming]
[faint rumbling]
[fire roaring]
[panting]
[Yona] Dad! Dad!
[Yona sobs]
Curtis.
Stay here.
[breathing heavily]